southwales-online.com 2016-01-17

# Privacy and Cookies - University of South Wales Online

The Programme for which you have applied is delivered in Collaborative Partnership with UNIC Online, which provides the Virtual Learning Environment and other services connected to Programme Delivery of the University of South Wales awards that have been approved for online delivery. It is the applicant’s responsibility to check with their national Higher Education regulatory body that an online degree is recognized in their home country.

The following terms and conditions also apply with respect to Unic Online Ltd:

Unic Online Ltd may occasionally change the terms and conditions of site usage.

BY USING THIS WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, YOU SHOULD NOT USE OUR WEBSITE.

**Privacy and cookies**

The Unic Online and UNICAF (‘the University) is committed to protecting the privacy of all users of this website. This policy applies to all University websites and how we govern and protect information that is obtained from those using this website.

By using and submitting information to this website you are consenting to the University collecting and holding information in accordance with this policy. The policy is subject to change and any future changes will be notified on this page.

**What information is collected?**

You do not have to register or provide any personal information when you visit the website to read or download information. Personal information will only be collected where you have knowingly provided personal details (name, address, email address, telephone number, etc.)

Certain types of information are automatically received whenever you view this website. Information that we automatically receive includes:

  *     Requested URL (Uniform Resource Locator)
  *     IP (Internet Protocol) address (this may or may not identify a specific computer)
  *     Domain name from which you access the internet
  *     Referring URL
  *     Software (browser/operating system) used to access the page
  *     Date and time pages were visited

**Use of cookies**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Below is a description of the types of cookies the website uses, including cookies from third party sites that we use to provide certain functionality on our web sites.

**Session Cookies**

The site uses a number of web frameworks to create and provide web sites. Most, if not all, of these frameworks provide session cookies to the users computer. These cookies enable movement throughout most of our secured sites without having to repeatedly log into different systems.

**Google Analytics**

The website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie in order to evaluate your use of our web sites and compiles reports for us on activity on our web sites.

Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**How to reject or delete this cookie**

**Cookies set by Third Party sites**

To support the content of our web sites, we sometimes embed photos, video and textual content from websites such as YouTube and Flickr. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. The site does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

**Moodle**

Moodle uses cookies for authentication/login purposes, and to tie the users requests together into a session as necessary for the web application’s functionality. They are purely functional cookies, no user identifying information is kept in our cookies at all. Thus none of that is stored on the users computer either.

It is inherent to the application that it tracks certain user activity for grading/auditing purposes. This is not done via cookies, but is tied to the authenticated user record.

User data submitted within courses is generally identifiable by user – as that is necessary for grading purposes. For some activities anonymous interaction may be possible at the discretion of the instructor.

Retention of such user-submitted data is governed by institutional policies for retention of academic records and is not controlled by Moodle.

No user data from Moodle instances is ever centrally collected by Moodle, with the exception of centrally hosted services that need to store user information including contact information or a document submission history. This information is however not accessible to anyone else, and Moodle does not share this data with third parties.

Third-party building blocks installed on the system may however link your Moodle user account to third party servers that also hold user-identifying information. Moodle does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

**Learning Objects**

Learning objects utilise session cookies to remember session details, as well as a cookie supplied by the internal load balancer to bind a session to a particular node. A desktop view cookie is also set, if the client is a mobile device and switches to a desktop view. Further to these, other cookies are set to track the general logged in state for the purpose of identifying session timeouts, and also to set the referrer accurately to the parent site when a client clicks on a link from within a specific blog entry or wiki page.

**eStream**

eStream uses cookies in order to track session information, and also to track specific user properties, such as authentication, general settings and permissions.

**How to change your cookie settings**

You can go to this website to change your settings. Just choose the appropriate link to the browser that you use.

**How we use your information**

The information that you provide enables the University to analyse the information to deliver services that you have requested and so that we can manage and improve the services on the website. Using the logging data we analyse demographic and other statistical information about user behaviour to analyse the popularity and effectiveness of our site.

The University also uses services from Google and Gravatar on this website. For further information on their privacy policies please visit the Google and Gravatar websites.

The University will not (nor will it allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tools to track or to collect personally identifiable information of visitors to this website. We will not sell, license or trade your personal information to others. We will not provide your personal information to direct marketing companies or other such organisations.

Personal information provided by you and any other information relating to you, will be held by the University and may be used for its own marketing purposes.

**Security**

The University employs security measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised use, access or disclosure.

We take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

**Disclosure of your information**

Authorised personnel within the University will be able to access the information that you provide us. We may also disclose your information to other third parties such as service providers, agents and associated organisations who act for us for the purposes set out within this Policy. All such third parties are prohibited from using this information except for providing these services to the University.

The information you provide will be held on our computers . It may be accessed by or given to third parties some of whom may be located outside the European Economic Area who act for us for the purposes set out in this policy. We will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Except as set out in this Policy, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent, unless required or permitted do so by law.

**Links to external websites**

This Privacy Policy only covers the University’s website, this website may contain links to other websites that are outside of the University’s control and are not covered by this privacy policy.

**Contact us**

If you have any queries concerning this Privacy Policy or the handling and management of your personal information please contact:

**Information Compliance Manager**

Email: [info@southwales-online.com](mailto:info@southwales-online.com)
